Guide to the Malcolm Goldstein Papers MSS.350
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series VI: Non-commercially Released Audio
  - Subseries A: Performances
    - "As it were, another" Studio Akustische Kunst, WDR Koln, April 22, 1998; ID: 350.0004 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0004)
      Benedikt Bitzendorfer, tonmeister (21,08")
      Original format: 1/4" audiocassette
    - "Barre Phillips and Malcolm Goldstein: Black Bot Munster", October 4, 2009; ID: 350.0005 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0005)
    - "Barre Phillips and Malcolm Goldstein: Live at Montevideo, Marseille", April 8, 2006; ID: 350.0006 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0006)
    - "Barre Phillips and Malcolm Goldstein: Wels Concert", October 6, 2009; ID: 350.0007 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0007)
      1) Intro W.W. (0'30"); 2)"On a Tuesday Evening" (20'15"); 3)"Just like real musicians" (9'08"); 4)"That's our favourite key" (8'54"); 5)"It's my speciality these days" (11'18"); 6)"Kleines Stuck ohne Titel" (7'40").
    - "Beginning articulations" part I of "On the edge of song", Music Gallery, Toronto, May 28, 2011; ID: 350.0008 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0008)
      Eve Egoyan, pianist. Premier (17'00")
    - "Bimhuis, Amsterdam: October Meeting 1991", ID: 350.0009 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0009)
      George Lewis, Trombone Anthony Braxton, saxophone Evan Parker, saxophone Malcolm Goldstein, violin Bernard Mixon, voice
    - "Bimhuis, Amsterdam: Solo Violin", November 5, 1990; ID: 350.0010 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0010)
    - Boulder Museum of Contemporary Art Concert Preliminary Mix 1, August 24, 2002; ID: 350.0011 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0011)
      1. Malcolm Intro (2:26) 2. Malcolm Intro Complete (2:52) 3.Configurations (10:24) 4.Speak Intro (0:41) 5.Gentle Rain (10:14) 6. Speak Intro (0:45) 7. Looking Backwards (15:46) 8. Speak Intro (0:46) 9.My feet my soul (9:41) 10.Speak Intro (0:46) 11. Improvised Encore (2:45) 12. Ken Thanks (0:33).
    - "A Breaking of Vessels, Becoming Song" Musical Elements premier, undated; ID: 350.0012 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0012)
      Robert Dick solo flute
    - "Cascades of the Brook: Bachwasserfall" Brooklyn Philharmonic, March 22, 1985; ID: 350.0013 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0013)
      Lukas Foss, conductor
    - "Cascades of the Brook: Bachwasserfall" Brooklyn Philharmonic/ Meet the Moderns series, March 22, 1985; ID: 350.0014 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0014)
      Lukas Foss: Conductor; Malcolm Goldstein: Violin Solo, NYC
    - Chapel Performance Space, Seattle, Washington, November 5, 2011; ID: 350.0015 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0015)
      Disc 1: 1) From "Fragments of the Wall" 2) "Configurations in darkness" Disc 2: 3) "On and on and always slowly nowhere" 4)"My feet is tired but my soul is rested" 5)"Two silences" 6)"Soundings" Credits: Eric Barber: Saxophones. Stuart Dempster: Trombone. Beth Fleenor: Clarinet and Bass Clarinet. Lori Goldston: Cello. Esther Sugai: Flute. Recorded by Steve Peters.
      Original format: 2 sound discs: digital; 4 3/4 in.
    - "Configurations in darkness" at HERE, NYC, August 10, 1995; ID: 350.0016 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0016)
      Improvisation on Serbo-Croation folk song. Excerpt from "Configurations in Darkness" NYC- HERE premier.
    - Cornish Institute '86, October 1986; ID: 350.0017 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0017)
      Side A: Soundings for Solo Violin; The Edges of Sound WIthin; Out of the Corners of My Eyes Side B: Yosha's Mornings Song; Qerneraq; Our Breath as Bones Premier The New Performance Group- Seattle
    - Cornish Institute- New Performance Group, Seattle, February 20, 1994; ID: 350.0018 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0018)
      Side A) 1. "Ishi/'man waxati' Soundings" (17'00") 2. "...out of changes: Keeping Still; Mountain" (23'30") Side B) 1. "gentle rain preceeding mushrooms (13'00") (with cold in throat!) 2. "that is poetry as" (2'30") 3. "Soweto Stomp" (12'00") with New Performance Group Seattle, WA
    - "Coyote's Breath Over the Water" ("La Souffle du Coyote a la Surface de l'Eau"), January 23, 1996; ID: 350.0019 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0019)
      Malcolm Goldstein composition, performance, mix (1995-1996) Studio 12 Recording: Yves LePage; Mix: Dennis Freceite; Production: Helene Drevost for Societe Radio-Canada "Le Navire Night"
    - "Coyote's Breath Over the Water" ("La Souffle du Coyote a la Surface de l'Eau") Final Mix Copy, January 23, 1996; ID: 350.0020 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0020)
      Malcolm Goldstein composition, performance, mix (1995-1996) Studio 12 Recording: Yves LePage; Mix: Dennis Freceite; Production: Helene Drevost Final Mix for performance use
    - "Dacapo Konzart- 200" Goldstein and Kaul, June 12, 1990; ID: 350.0021 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0021)
    - "Darkness becoming narrative" performed by L'Archipel Nocturne at Musique Action, Vandoeuvre-les-Nancy, France, May 19, 2010; ID: 350.0022 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0022)
      Recorded by Yannick Herpin. (27'05")
    - DRAM (New World) Radio Program, February, 2011; ID: 350.0023 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0023)
      (60'48").
    - "The edges of sound within" WDR studio concert and performance, September 28, 1985; ID: 350.0024 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0024)
      The edges of sound within (19'55") and WDR Concert performance Inspielband (19'48")
    - "Electronic/tape collage music" Judson Dance Theater, 1963, 1966, 1967; ID: 350.0025 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0025, Case 350.0025)
      1) "It seemed to me" (5'43") 1963, for Arlene Rothlein's dance. 2) "Judson #6 Piece" (6'43") 1963, for Ruth Emerson's dance. 3) "Sheep Meadow" (6'42") 1966, for anti-Vietnam war setting. 4)"Images from Cheng Hsieh" (15'51") 1967, for Carol Marcy's dance; also can be played with "Violence of Small Sounds".
      Original format: (1 sound disc) digital, 4 3/4 in.
      An access CD is available for listening in the reading room.
    - "An enactment of absence" (compilation), 1984, 1995, 1996; ID: 350.0026 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0026)
      1) "An enactment of absence" (18'52") 1995. 2)"Soundings for solo violin" (11'40"). 3)"as it were" (18'05") December, 1996 with Malcolm Goldstein, Joseph Kubera, Robert Black, Charles Wood at Merkin Concert Hall, NYC. 4)"Cascades of the Brook: Bachwasserfall" (12'42") 1984, Brooklyn Philharmonic, Lukas Foss conductor.
    - Experimental Intermedia Foundation, November 21, 1987; ID: 350.0027 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0027)
      Side One: 1) Soundings (4'15") 2) Edges of Sound Within 3) from "The Life Cycles of Stones" (15'00") premier version Side Two: 1) from "Life Cycles of Stones" (5'00") completed 2) Elegia (se hable espanol) (40'00") first pt. 30 premier with Nancy Guevara
    - Experimental Intermedia Foundation, March 20, 1993; ID: 350.0028 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0028)
      Side A: 1) "Soundings" 16'00 2) "Ishi" Side B: 3) "gentle rain preceeding mushrooms" NYC premier 14'30" 4) "qaumaneq; shaking with joy" world premier 15'30"
    - Experimental Intermedia Foundation, March 8, 2005; ID: 350.0029 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0029)
      1) "Ishi/'man waxati' Soundings" (14'50"). 2)"Harscrabble Songs" (10'07"). 3)"approaching the Wall (Li Po text)" (7'32") premier Li Po Text song as a work in progress. 4)"Where are we going when we're standing still, looking backwards?!" (17'40"). 5)"Soundings" (10'52").
    - Exploratorium Berlin, November 1, 2006; ID: 350.0030 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0030)
      "Fragments of the Wall"; "Where are we going when we're standing still looking backwards?!"; "qerneraq: our breath as bones"; "Hardscrabble Songs (song #4)"; "Soundings"
    - Festival Suoni per il popolo, Montreal, June 3, 2008; ID: 350.0031 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0031)
      1) "Hardscrabble Songs" (13'05"). 2)"A New Song of many faces for In These Times" (17'52"). Quatuor Bozzini.
    - "Fiddling Cow Bells", June 13, 1988; ID: 350.0032 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0032)
      "Fiddling Cow Bells" No dynamic changes
    - "Fragments of the Wall" excerpt from performance at Chapelle historique du Bon Pasteur, February 11, 2009; ID: 350.0033 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0033)
      1) Bosnia-Herzogovinia folk songs and improvisation 2)"Fooling the Killers" poetry of Taha Muhammad Ali 3)"Dance" (13'38"). Recorded by Matthieu Belanger
    - "Fragments of the Wall" premier from Radio France Recording, September 12, 2008; ID: 350.0034 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0034)
      Ce vaut jamais le reel festival. Instants Chavires, Montreal France. With Maclolm Goldstein: violin, Jim Denley: Saxophone, Thierry Madiot: trombone, Louis-Michael Marion: cb, Matthias Kaul: percussion, Li-Ping Ting:danse.
    - "Fragments of the Wall", undated; ID: 350.0163 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0163)
      "Images of Cheng Hsieh" (15'51"); "Fooling the Killers" Taha Muhammad Ali reading (2'00")
      Original format: (1 sound disc ) digital; 4 3/4 in.
    - "Free at Last" #1, January 16, 1986; ID: 350.0035 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0035)
      A) Been in the storm so long B) Funeral- Archie Shepp, Soweto Stomp- Malcolm Goldstein Northweatern University, Boston. (Dolby).
    - "Free at Last" #2, January 16, 1986; ID: 350.0036 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0036)
      A) "My feet is tired, but my sould is rested"- Malcolm Goldstein B) "...that hung like fire on heaven" Malcolm Goldstein (23'15")
    - "Fylkingen", April 10, 1984; ID: 350.0037 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0037)
      1) Soundings, entrance 2) jade mountain soundings (13'00") 3) from center of rainbow soungings RR recording engineer: Rone Sundvall
    - "Hues of the Golden Ascending", April 10, 1981; ID: 350.0038 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0038)
      premier Macalester College flute ensemble (20'20")
    - "Hues of the Golden Ascending", April 10, 1981; ID: 350.0039 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0039)
      Premier Macalester College flute ensemble (20'58")
    - "Hues of the Golden Ascending", April 1981; ID: 350.0040 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0040)
      Flute Ensemble recorded at Macalester College
      Original format: 7 1/2 IPS stereo copy
    - "Illuminations..." and other pieces from the early 1960's, ID: 350.0041 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0041)
      Side A: 1) Illuminations from Fantastic Gardens a) Dolby C b) No Dolby (missing beginning) Side B: 1) Ludlow Blues (wind instrument and electronic tape) 2) Emanations (violin and cello) 3) Stillpoint (brass quintet) 4) Paradoxes (violin, trumpet, bassoon, vocal. All taped from single LP made in the '60s tapes in Vermont (scratchy)
    - "Illuminations from Fantastic Gardens", April 24, 1964; ID: 350.0042 (Box 43, Media ID: 350.0042)
      Tone Roads concert, New School for Social Research NYC (first concert performance). Vocalists: Beth Cuje, Norma Marder, Robert Ramieri and John Wilson. (12'55").
    - "Images from Cheng Hsieh" and "Violence of Small Sounds", undated; ID: 350.0043 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0043)
      Stereo Tape Collage (performance tape copy)
    - "Improvisation: Goldstein with Philip Corner" NYC, November 14, 1991; December 1, 1991; ID: 350.0044 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0044)
      With Laura Donnelly dancing and Phoebe Neville dancing.
    - "Interlude(s)" Universite Bishop's Radio Canada., 2000, 2001; ID: 350.0045 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0045)
      2) S. Ferguson "Preperation" 3) M. Goldstein "Interlude(s)" (7'35") 4) O.Larue "Poussierres" 5) J.F. Laporte "L'Invisible piano"
    - "Ishi/time changing spaces" WDR horspiel, February 18, 1988; ID: 350.0046 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0046)
      Westdeutscher Rundfunk Koln Horspiel/Studio Master Tape
    - "Jade Mountain Soundings", October 17, 1995; ID: 350.0047 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0047)
      Technician: Yves LePage Realization: Helene Premt Studio 12 Pour "Le Navine Night", 13 minutes
    - "Jade Mountain Soundings" DRS (multiple tracks), 1987; ID: 350.0048 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0048)
      Jade Mountain Soundings (21'45") multiple tracks with live performance at Neve Horizonte Concert Berne (recorded by DRS) Switzerland
    - "John Cage: 'Ryoanji' and 'Score and 23 Parts'", September 19, 1992; ID: 350.0049 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0049)
      HR Ensemble for New Music- Malcolm Goldstein, director Concert at Anarchic Harmony festival- music of John Cage, Frankfurt
    - Klangforum Wien: Konzerthaus Wien/ Mozart saal, April 6, 2006; ID: 350.0050 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0050)
      1) "A cultivation of field" (12'00") 2)"What can be said of our differences?" (18'50")
    - Klangforum Wien: Musik Triennale Koln, April 29, 2007; ID: 350.0051 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0051)
      1) "A cultivation of field" (13'40") 2)"What can be said of our differences?" (21'32")
    - Klangzeit Munster: Grenzgange fest, Cuba, October 26, 2006; ID: 350.0052 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0052)
      "Configurations in Darkness"; "My feet is tired but my soul is rested"; "Soundings" (9'44")
    - Knitting Factory, NYC, January 10, 1988; ID: 350.0053 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0053)
      violin solo: 18'05" and 10'00"
    - Knitting Factory, NYC, November 13, 1988; ID: 350.0054 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0054)
      Goldstein- solo violin
    - La Sala Rossa, Montreal: solo violin concert, September 29, 2011; ID: 350.0055 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0055)
      1) Intro talk 2)"Soundings" 3)"Eight Whiskus" John Cage 4)"gentle rain preceding mushrooms" 5)"Sounding the Fragility of Line 6)"Soundings" 7)"on and on and always slowly nowhere"
    - Le Port de Tete, Montreal, November 13, 2011; ID: 350.0056 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0056)
      1) "Mais une oiseau qui n'est pas chante" from "Fragments of the Wall" (6'15"). 2)"On and on and always slowly nowhere" (23'30") 3)"Soundings" (11'06") 4)"on a journey...wandering still" (7'20"). Recorded by Mathieu Belanger.
    - "The Life Cycle of Stones", undated; ID: 350.0057 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0057)
      collage part (Track I and II) stereo cassette Master
    - "The Life Cycle of Stones", June 21, 1989; ID: 350.0058 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0058)
      from Reel I: loop 5'20"
    - "The Life Cycle of Stones", June 21, 1987; ID: 350.0059 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0059)
      from Reel II: loop c. 7'20"
    - " Liu Fang and Malcolm Goldstein: Duo Improvization", October 4, 2003; ID: 350.0060 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0060)
      Recorded by Eric Lewis.
    - "Logos/Ghent", March 13, 1989; ID: 350.0061 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0061)
      Side I: 1) "Ishi/'man waxati' Sounding" (21'00") 2) "Out of the Corners of My Eyes (18'30") Side 2: 1) Sounding the Fragility of Line (16'00") 2) Soundings (19'00")
    - "Ludlow Blues", 1963; ID: 350.0062 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0062)
      For Flute, Alto Saxophone, Trombone, and Electronic Sounds. (Transferred from Cassette tape recording).
    - "L'usine" Concert solo with Rainer Wiens, March 1996; ID: 350.0063 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0063)
      A) Duet with Rainer Wiens (23'25") B) Soundings for Solo Violin (20'40") at "L'usine" Montreal
    - "Marin's Lied" WDR Koln- Horspiel, November 1984; ID: 350.0064 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0064)
      Marin's Lied Illuminiert (29'20")
    - "Marin's Song, Illuminated", undated; ID: 350.0065 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0065)
      Tape Collage Part
    - "Marin's Song Illuminated" (Alternative Museum Performance) with "Vermont Night Song/Soundings", 1981, 1983; ID: 350.0066 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0066)
      A) Marin's Song, Illuminated (Alternative Museum performance) 1981- edited for radio broadcast B) Vermont Night Song and Soundings (Center of Rainbow Sounding)/ Experimental Intermedia Foundation May 12, 1983 (18'45")
    - "Marin's Song, Illuminated: fragments and variations", March 6, 1982; ID: 350.0067 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0067)
      xx
    - "Marin's Song, Illuminated: fragments and variations" at Experimental Intermedia Foundation, April 3, 1981; ID: 350.0068 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0068)
    - "Matthias Kaul and Malcolm Goldstein Duo: SWR2 Now Jazz Summit" Basel, April 28, 2005; ID: 350.0069 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0069)
    - "Matthias Kaul and Malcolm Goldstein" Montrevil, France, September 17, 2008; ID: 350.0070 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0070)
      Radio France Recording: Instants Chavires.
      Currently unavailable.
    - "A meditation/ response to Charles Ives' 'Unanswered Question'" live installation performance at Ellen Gallery, Concordia University, Montreal, November 18, 2006; ID: 350.0071 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0071)
      Recorded by Mathieu Belanger.
    - "Meditation in Darkness" Alison Knowles, May 2002; ID: 350.0072 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0072)
      2 Audio Tracks. Track 1) 4:06" Track 2) 3:59"
    - Merkin Concert Hall, NYC: Interpretations concert series, December 4, 1996; ID: 350.0073 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0073)
      Side A: "an enactment of absence" world premier (1995) [18'52"]; "Sounding for Solo Violin" [11'40"] Side B: "as it were" (1996) [18'05"] Malcolm Goldstein: violin, Joseph Kubera: piano, Robert Black: bass, Charles Wood: percussion
    - Mills College Concert, February 12, 1997; ID: 350.0074 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0074)
      Side A: 1) from "configurations in darkness" (14'25") 2) "gentle rain preceeding mushrooms" Side B: 1) "Ishi/'man waxati' Soundings" (19'05") 2) Soundings (9'00") DAT original at MIlls
    - "Montreal Miniature" and "Art Talks" interview, February and March1997; ID: 350.0075 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0075)
      1) "Montreal Miniature" for "Montreal Sounds Like" February 19, 1997 CBC Montreal, (5'00") Master Cassette 2) "Art Talks" CBC/AM interview and premier AM radio broadcast March 1, 1997 with Shelley Pomerance
    - "Musik am Sonntagnachmittag XLV" Violin Solo, December 3, 1995; ID: 350.0076 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0076)
      A) "Ishi/'man waxati'"(18'10"), "gentle rain preceeding mushrooms" (12'30") B) "my feet is tired bit my soul is rested" (18'19"), "Soundings" (11'35"), "Trinity" (Ornette Coleman)
    - Musique Action: Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, May 17, 2002; ID: 350.0077 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0077)
      "Ishi/'man waxati' Soundings"; "my feet is tired but my soul is rested"(11'20"); "Soundings"(10'36"); "where are we going when we're standing still, looking backwards?!" with introduction in French; Short Encore.
    - "A New Song of many faces for In These Times" The Locrian Chamber Players String Quartet, NYC, February 7, 2008; ID: 350.0078 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0078)
      (18'52").
    - "A New Song of many faces for In These Times" Quatuor Bozzini, Theatre La Chapelle, May 2002; ID: 350.0079 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0079)
      Clemens Merkel; Genevieve Beaudry; Stephanie Bozzini; Isabelle Bozzini. Societe Radio Canada Recording.
    - "Of Sky Bright Mushrooms Bursting in My Head" dress rehearsal recording, July 3, 1984; ID: 350.0080 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0080)
      New Music America, Hartford used for NPR and Europe distribution (Relache)
    - "On withered fields, wandering still" Montreal, 2010; ID: 350.0081 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0081)
      L'Oubli de l'air installation by Lani Maestro
    - "On withered fields, wandering still" Montreal, 2010; ID: 350.0082 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0082)
      "L'Oubli de l'air" installation by Lani Maestro at Fonderie Darling. "The 2 CDs, as separate tracks, played simultaneously with continuous playback, allowing for new relations of sonic material to occur over time"
      Original format: (2 sound discs) digital, 4 3/4 in.
    - "On the first day of Spring..." Malcolm Goldstein, Discovery, March 20, 1981; ID: 350.0083 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0083)
      a) Interviews with Joe Bloom b) On the first day of Spring there were forty pianos (8 min.) c) Soundings for solo violin d) Interview e) On the first day... (17 min.) f) Interview g) Soundings (8.5 min.) premier performance
    - "...out of changes; Keeping Still; Mountain" rehearsal, April 10, 1997; ID: 350.0084 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0084)
      Rehearsal, L'Art pour L'Art- Winsen for Hamburg Concert cassette copy from DAT original (22'50") (begins after a minute of silence)
    - "Portrait de Malcolm Goldstein" France Musique A l'improviste, Anne Montaron, September 26, 2008; ID: 350.0085 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0085)
      Radio France. Chargee de realisation Beatrice Trichet, Assistante Dorothee Goll.
    - Pro Musica Nova, Bremen, May 8, 1986; ID: 350.0086 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0086)
      Side 1: Soundings (11'00"), Marin's Song, Illuminated (31'00") Side 2: The Edges of Sound Within (20'16"), Out of the Corners of my Eyes (8'43")
    - "qerneraq..." as in "Topography of a Sound Mind", May 1991; ID: 350.0087 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0087)
      "qerneraq; our breath as bones" and padloq text (English and Greek) from "Topography of a Sound Mind" WDR Koln
    - "Quatuor d'occasion" Improvisations at Wilder and Davis, Montreal, May 5, 2012; ID: 350.0088 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0088)
      Malcolm Goldstein, Josh Zubot, Jean Rene, Emilie Girard-Charest. Recording by Matthieu Belanger.
    - "Rainer Wiens and Malcolm Goldstein: Demo CD" Montreal, undated; ID: 350.0089 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0089)
      Malcolm Goldstein: Violin; Rainer Wiens: Prepared Guitar.
    - "Rainer Wiens and Malcolm Goldstein" Cagibi, Montreal., April 14, 2009; ID: 350.0090 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0090)
      Violin and Prepared Guitar Recorded by Mathieu Belanger.
    - "Rainer Wiens and Malcolm Goldstein" Cagibi, Montreal., January 20, 2009; ID: 350.0091 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0091)
      Mardi Spaghetti. Recorded by Matthieu Belanger.
    - "Rainer Wiens and Malcolm Goldstein: Casa del Popolo" Montreal, October 26, 2005; ID: 350.0092 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0092)
      Violin and Prepared Guitar. Recorded by Matthieu Belanger.
    - "Rainer Wiens and Malcolm Goldstein: Casa del Popolo" Montreal., January 4, 2006; ID: 350.0093 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0093)
      Improvising Montreal Series. Recorded by Matthieu Belanger.
    - "Rainer Wiens and Malcolm Goldstein: Improvising Montreal Series, Casa del Popole" Montreal., January 3, 2007; ID: 350.0094 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0094)
    - Real Art Ways concert, December 5, 1987; ID: 350.0095 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0095)
      "Soundings"; "from The Life Cycles of Stones"; "Out of the Corners of My Eyes"; "The Edges of Sound Within"; "Vision Tree Fragment"
    - "Regarding the Tower of Babel" Hessischer Rundfunk Ensemble fur Neue Musik, September 17, 1997; ID: 350.0096 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0096)
      Premier Theaterhaus Frankfurt.
    - "Renga"- Composite, complete music., undated; ID: 350.0097 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0097)
      Composite of recordings 1, 2, 3, and 4
    - "Renga" Fall mix- Le Navire Night: La Metamorphose de la Source, January 18, 1998; ID: 350.0098 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0098)
      3 Improvisations- Mix for broadcast Malcolm Goldstein, Jean Rene, Rainer Wiens, Rene Lussier, Normand Guilbeault
    - "Renga" Le Navire Night: La Metamorphose de la Source (1 of 2), January 18, 1998; ID: 350.0099 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0099)
      Malcolm Goldstein, Jean Rene, Rainer Wiens, Rene Lussier, Normand Guilbeault Studio 12: Realization: Helene Prevost Techn: P. Plante and J.P. Bolduc
    - "Renga" Le Navire Night: La Metamorphose de la Source [2 of 2], January 18, 1998; ID: 350.0100 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0100)
    - "Resonances de Babel" French/English version of "Regarding the Tower of Babel", November 26, 2004; ID: 350.0101 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0101)
      Premier The Babel Ensemble, La Sala Rossa, Montreal. Jean Derome: Flute; Malcolm Goldstein: Violin; Frank Lozano: Saxophone; Jean Rene: Viola; Rainer Wiens: Guitar.
    - Roulette #1, March 11, 1984; ID: 350.0102 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0102)
      Side A: 1) Soundings 2) Vision Tree Fragment Side B: 2) Vision Tree Fragment (continued) 3) Jade Mountain Soundings
    - Roulette #2, March 11, 1984; ID: 350.0103 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0103)
      Side A: 1) El nino rojo 2) Soundings (coda)
    - Roulette (at Location One) NYC, October 15, 2003; ID: 350.0104 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0104)
      "Variation 2" Johannes Wallmann; "Opium fur T" Matthias Kaul (9'30"); "Two Silences" Malcolm Goldstein (23'40")(world premier with intro and comments); "-Z" Hespos ensemble, improvisation. L'Art pour l'art.